The first mission to the Trojan asteroids …
A prelaunch milestone for our Artemis I mission …
And highlighting a few of our NASA centers …
a few of the stories to tell you about – This Week at NASA!
We have engine ignition
Release.
Engine at full thrust.
On October 16th, we launched our Lucy spacecraft from Cape Canaveral Space Force
Station, in Florida.
Lucy is the first space mission
to the Trojan asteroids,
a diverse population of small bodies
believed to be remnants of our early
solar system, that are trapped
in a stable orbit with Jupiter.
The mission could help revolutionize
what we know about the origins
and formation of our solar system
and its planets.
Learn more about the mission
at: nasa.gov/lucy.
Teams working inside the Vehicle Assembly
Building at our Kennedy Space Center
added the Orion spacecraft’s stage
adapter to the top of the Space
Launch System or SLS rocket
for our upcoming Artemis I mission.
They will add Orion
and its launch abort system
on top of the stage
adapter to complete the Artemis I stack.
Artemis I will be the first flight test
around the Moon of the SLS
rocket And Orion spacecraft
as an integrated system.
Our Administrator Bill Nelson
and Deputy Administrator
Pam Melroy recently
visited NASA centers in California.
They toured our Ames
Research Center on Oct. 12
to hear about climate-related research
– including wildfire prevention
and reduction of emissions with the use of
air traffic management tools.
The next day at our Armstrong Flight
Research Center they participated
in activities to celebrate the center’s
75th anniversary –
including the opening
of a 25-year-old time capsule.
Finally, on Oct. 14,
they stopped by our Jet Propulsion
Laboratory for a climate summit
with elected officials.
While there, they also were updated
on plans for our Perseverance
rover and Ingenuity helicopter on Mars.
NASA's James Webb Space Telescope
successfully arrived
in French Guiana on October 12th
after a 16 day journey at sea.
After Webb is driven
to its launch site in Koru,
it will be prepped for its targeted
December 18th launch.
From its vantage point in space,
about one million miles from Earth,
the world’s largest and most complex
space science observatory
is expected to capture
images of the early universe
that will transform our understanding
of our place in the cosmos.
Learn more about the mission
at nasa.gov/webb.
Officials from NASA and other industry leaders gathered in Huntsville, Alabama Oct. 12-14
for the 14th annual
Wernher von Braun Memorial Symposium.
This year’s theme was, “United:
A Foundation Delivered,
The Future Enabled.”
The event featured discussion
about the space science and exploration
progress made to date,
as well as the plans and goals
for future space endeavors.
That's what's up this week at NASA.
For more on these and other stories,
follow us on the web at nasa.gov/twan.